Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Young, Katherine, April 2014-ongoing; Young, Katherine, 1980-; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about her compositions and projects; a calendar of her events; a gallery of images of the artist; a discography of her published albums; and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The crawl also includes the composer's blog and the website for Till by Turning, a chamber music ensemble made up of performers Amy Cimini, Erica Dicker, Emily Manzo, and Katherine Young.
  Audio and video files in the artist's website were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Katherine Young (b. 1980) is a bassoonist and composer of electro-acoustic music that features improvisation. She often performs both as a soloist as well as in collaboration with improvised groups. Among Young's notable works are Resonance and the Inhibition of, an 8-channel outdoor sound installation using original text; fragments of PhD dissertations; an oral history interview; and sounds performed by different vocalists. Young is also a scholar of music with a focus on the incorporation of idiosyncratic electronics and improvisation in contemporary notated music. She has also written about Anthony Braxton's operatic work.
- Young, Nina C., February 2015-ongoing; Young, Nina C., 1984-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ninacyoung.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; a list of works with embedded audio files; a discography; selected media with excerpts of her works, including audio and video files; interviews; talks and podcasts where the artist participated; press features; a gallery of images of the artist; and contact information.
  Nina C. Young (b. 1984) is a composer of electronic, vocal, and acoustic music for large and small ensemble performance, as well as for soloists and duos. Young also composes music for films; creates sound installations; and site-specific collaborations with other artists. Examples of recent works by Young include private, stolen time, a piece for a large ensemble of 13 musicians; echoes, before and after, a pocket concerto for solo violin and chamber ensemble; and Eclipses, an electroacoustic work for 2-channel fixed media.
- Z, Pamela, February 2015-ongoing; Z, Pamela, 1956-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of pamelaz.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Pamela Z (b. 1956) is a composer and media artist who works with voice, live electronic processing, sampled sound, and video. Z creates small and large-scale multimedia works in varied settings and often combines experimental vocal techniques, operatic singing, found objects, and text in her pieces. She was one of the first artists to experiment with live digital looping techniques.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography; a list of events; videos; photos; descriptions of her works; and recordings. It also contains her contact information; links to the websites of friends and collaborators; and Pamela Z's newsletter titled PZ Gazzetta.
- Ziporyn, Evan, February 2014- ongoing
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ziporyn.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Evan Ziporyn (b. 1959) is a composer, conductor, and clarinetist specializing in post-minimalistic music. His works draw from different cultures and music genres. Ziporyn was also the musician to record the definitive version of Steve Reich's multi-clarinet piece New York Counterpoint in 1996, which won a Grammy award in 1998.
  The website contains a news page, a biography, score excerpts, a list of projects, an events calendar, a list of albums, press reviews, and contact information.